로스가 내게 키스했어
Ross kissed me.
어머!
어쩜, 세상에!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
정말 짜릿했어
It was unbelievable!
세상에! 세상에!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
전부 얘기해 줘
Let's hear everything.
Monica, get the wine
and unplug the phone.
- 와인 가져오고 전화선 뽑아
- 알았어
Rachel, does this end well
or do we need to get tissues?
레이첼, 해피엔딩이야?
아님 휴지 가져올까?
해피엔딩이야
It ended very well.
아직 시작하지 마!
나 빼면 안 돼!
Do not start without me!
Okay. All right.
Let's hear about the kiss.
키스에 대해 먼저 말해 봐
입만 살짝 댄 거였어?
Was it a soft brush
against your lips...
...or was it a "I gotta have you now"
kind of thing?
아님 금방 잡아먹을 듯했어?
Well, at first it was really intense,
you know? And then....
처음엔 아주 강렬했고
Oh, God. And then we just
sort of sunk into it.
나중엔 둘 다 무아지경이었어
로스가 널 안았어?
양손으로 등을 감쌌냐고
So was he holding you?
Or were his hands on your back?
No, actually, first
they started out on my waist...
처음엔 허리를 먼저 잡고
...and then they slid up
and were in my hair.
천천히 올라와서
내 머리를 매만졌어
And...
그리고 나서 키스했지
...then I kissed her.
Tongue?
진한 걸로?
-Yeah.
-Cool.
- 그럼
- 잘했어
The One With the List
이 녀석을 보라고!
All right, check out this bad boy!
Twelve megabytes of RAM,
500-megabyte hard drive...
램이 12메가에
하드는 무려 500메가
... built-in spreadsheet capabilities...
오피스 프로그램에
28,000BPS 모뎀이
장착돼 있다고!
...and a modem that transmits
at over 28,000 BPS.
뭐에 쓰려고?
What will you use it for?
Games and stuff.
오락할 거야
괜찮은 일자리가 없어
There are no jobs.
There are no jobs for me.
Oh, wait, here's one.
하나 찾았다
-Would you be willing to cook naked?
-There's an ad for a naked chef?
나체로 요리할 수 있어?
나체 요리사를 구해?
No, but if you'll cook naked, then
you might be willing to dance naked.
아니, 나체로 요리 할 정도면
춤도 출 수 있을 것이고
그럼 짭짤하지
And then....
안녕
어제 애무 어땠어?
So how'd you make out last night?
That is funny.
That is painfully funny.
생각하면 죽도록 좋지
하지만 죽고 싶어
No, wait, wait.
Yeah, that's just painful.
Wait a minute.
I thought last night was great.
아주 좋았다고 하던데
좋았어
Yeah, it was.
But I get home...
한데 집 테이블에 놓인
줄리의 식염수를 보니까
...and I see Julie's saline solution
on my night table...
정신이 번쩍 들더라고
...and I think,
"My God! What am I doing?"
날 진심으로 사랑해 주는
줄리와 열애 중인데
Here I am with Julie,
this incredible, great woman...
...who I care about
and who cares about me...
...and I'm just
throwing all that away?
이 행복을 포기해야 돼?
식염수 한 병에
그걸 깨달았어?
You got all that
from saline solution?
레이첼 생각도 해야지
오빠와 레이첼!
Wait. We're talking about Rachel.
You and Rachel.
레이첼을 10년 동안
짝사랑했지만
I've been dreaming about
me and Rachel for 10 years.
But now I'm with Julie.
내겐 지금 줄리가 있어
So it's like, me and Julie,
me and Rachel.
줄리와 레이첼을 놓고
줄다리기하는 꼴이라고
줄리와 레이첼...
Me and Julie, me and Rach
레이첼!
Rachel! Rachel.
-Hey, you.
-How are you?
- 안녕
- 기분 어때?
Good. How are you?
- 좋아, 넌?
- 나도 좋아
Good.
- 안녕, 자기
- 어서 와, 줄리
-Hi, honey.
-Hi, Julie. Hi, Julie?
줄리!
Julie!
어때?
How are you?
- 좋아
- 그래
Good.
다들 모였네
So everybody's here.
Everybody's good.
모두 아주 좋다고
노래하려고 했어?
Were you gonna play something?
- 사실은...
- 불러!
-Well, actually
-Play it!
All right.
좋아
- 원래 렌즈를 꼈어요?
- 네?
-Julie, I didn't know you wore lenses.
-What?
Okay. Hi.
안녕하세요!
거기도 안녕?
Hello. Hi. Okay.
제가 만든 노래인데
삼각관계에 관한 거죠
This is a song about a love triangle...
... between three people I made up.
제목은...
'그중 둘이 간밤에 키스했네'
It's called
"Two of Them Kissed Last Night."
여자는 베티
남자는 닐이라고 하자
There was a girl
We'll call her Betty
And a guy
Let's call him Neil
다시 한번 강조하지만
이 얘기는 허구라네
Now I can't stress
This point too strongly
This story isn't real
닐은 누구를 차야 할지
결정해야만 하네
Now our Neil must decide
Who will be the girl that he casts aside
진정으로 사랑하는
베티일까?
Will Betty be the one
Who he loves truly
Or will it be the one
Who we'll call Loolie
아님 룰리란 이름의
여자가 차일까?
닐은 결정해야 하네
He must decide
Even though I made him up
내가 지어낸 인물이지만
결정해야 한다네
Well, this is a nice resume.
경력이 아주 화려하네요
Nice, nice, nice.
아주 좋아요
좋아 죽을 지경이에요
Muy impressivo.
광고에 명확치 않던데
무슨 일이죠?
Mr. Rastatter, what does this
job entail? The ad wasn't clear.
Macholate.
마콜릿!
-I'm sorry?
-Macholate.
- 네?
- 마콜릿!
합성 초콜릿 대체물이죠
It's a synthetic chocolate substitute.
Go ahead, try a piece.
한번 먹어 봐요
We think Macholate is
even better than chocolate.
마콜릿이 초콜릿보다
더 맛있어요
좋아요
All right.
그렇죠?
부서지는 맛이 있네요
I love how it crumbles.
-You see, chocolate doesn't do that.
-No, ma'am.
- 초콜릿은 녹잖아요
- 그래요
곧 식품의약청의 승인도
떨어질 거예요
We should be getting
our FDA approval any day now.
Hopefully, in time for Thanksgiving.
추수감사절 이전으로
기대하고 있는데
The way we see it,
chocolate dominates...
우린 이렇게 생각해요
초콜릿은 이미 명절의
주요 단골식품이 됐죠
...your major food-preparation holidays.
Easter, Christmas, what have you.
부활절, 성탄절 등등
마케팅을 제대로 하면
But given the right marketing...
...we can make Thanksgiving
the Macholate holiday.
추수감사절을 '마콜릿절'로
바꿀 수 있을 거예요
Wow.
Aren't you gonna swallow that?
안 삼켜요?
Just waiting for it to stop bubbling.
거품이 사라지고 나면요
Isn't that great?
정말 특이하죠?
그건 그렇고...
Well, anyhow...
...we're looking for chefs
who can create Thanksgiving recipes.
추수감사절 요리를
창조할 요리사를 구하는데
You interested?
관심 있으세요?
물론... 이죠!
Abso-...
... -lutely!
전 요리와 추수감사절을
좋아해요
I love creating recipes,
I love Thanksgiving, and now...
... I love Macholate.
이제 마콜릿도 좋아하고요
정말이에요?
Really?
뒷맛이 뭐랄까...
성탄절까지 생생하겠어요
Especially that aftertaste.
I tell you...
...that'll last you till Christmas.
How about Macholate mousse?
마콜릿 무스 어때?
It's not...
...very Thanksgiving-y.
추수감사절에는
잘 안 어울릴 것 같아
순례자 마콜릿 무스 어때?
How about Pilgrim Macholate mousse?
What makes it Pilgrim?
순례자를 어떻게
맛으로 표현해?
We'll put buckles on it.
위에다 버클을 얹지 뭐
- 로스한테 전화 왔어?
- 아니
Did Ross call?
No, I'm sorry.
왜 전화를 안 하지?
Why didn't he call?
줄리를 택한 게 틀림없어
He's gonna stay with Julie.
로스는 줄리를 택하고
줄리는 이러겠지
He's gonna stay with her
and she'll be:
'안녕, 로스가 날 찍었어'
"Hi, I'm Julie. Ross picked me.
We'll get married and have lots
of kids and dig up stuff together!"
'우린 결혼해서 애 낳고
발굴도 할 거다'
No offense, but that
sounds nothing like her.
기분 나쁘게 듣지 마
하나도 안 똑같애
어떡해야 할지를 모르겠어
이건 악몽이야!
What am I gonna do?
This is like a complete nightmare!
그래, 엄청 힘들겠다
'두 여자가 날 사랑해! '
I know. This must be so hard.
"Oh, no! Two women love me!
They're both gorgeous,
my wallet's too small for my 50s...
둘 다 예쁘고 섹시해
다 거느리기엔 지갑이 가볍고
다이아몬드 구두도 작아!
...and my diamond shoes are too tight!"
- 내 생각인데...
- 내 노트북 건드리지 마!
-Here's a thought
-Don't ever touch the computer.
들어 봐, 로스
딱 두 마디만 할게
Ross, listen.
I got two words for you:
Threesome.
3인 성교!
이성적으로 대처해야 해
목록을 작성해 따져 보자고
Let's get logical about this.
We'll make a list.
"Rachel and Julie: Pros and Cons."
'레이첼과 줄리의 장단점'
둘의 이름을 다른 글씨체로
쓰고 칸에 다른 색을 넣을게
We'll put their names
in different fonts...
...and I can use different
colors for each column.
그냥 펜으로 하자
Can't we use a pen?
No, Amish boy.
안 돼, 이 컴맹아!
Let's start with the cons
because they're more fun.
단점부터 시작하자
그게 더 재미있으니까
레이첼 먼저
Rachel first.
모르겠어
I don't know.
I mean....
약간 철이 없기는 해
All right, I guess you can say
she's a little spoiled sometimes.
You could say that.
시작 좋고
아무 생각 없는 것 같고
I guess, sometimes
she's a little ditzy, you know?
너무 외모에 신경을 써
And I've seen her be a little
too into her looks.
줄리와 난 공통점이 많아
둘 다 고생물학을 전공했지
And Julie and I have
a lot in common...
... because we're both
paleontologists, right?
But Rachel's just a waitress.
레이첼은 웨이트리스고
Waitress.
웨이트리스...
다 적었다!
너희들 오락할래?
Got it.
You guys want to play Doom?
아냐, 이거 계속하자
Or we could keep doing this.
또?
What else?
I don't know.
모르겠어
맞다, 발목이 좀 두꺼워
Oh! Her ankles are a little chubby.
이번엔 줄리 차례야
줄리의 단점은?
Okay, let's do Julie.
What's wrong with her?
She's not Rachel.
레이첼이 아니잖아
This is pumpkin pie
with a Macholate crust.
마콜릿을 입힌 호박 파이야
This is Macholate cranberry cake,
and these are Macholate-chip cookies.
마콜릿 크랜베리 케이크
이건 마콜릿 쿠키
인디언들 주식이었지
Just like the lndians served.
Oh, my God!
맙소사!
"Oh, my God" good?
너무 맛있다고?
Oh, my God! I can't believe
you let me put this in my mouth.
어떻게 이런 걸
먹으라고 주니?
Sweet Lord!
This is what evil must taste like!
하느님 아버지!
완전히 악마 맛이야!
I tell you, it won't print.
프린트가 안 돼요!
I pressed that button, like, 100 times.
백 번도 더 눌렀어요!
For a hotline, you're not so hot.
긴급서비스 팀이
이렇게 느려 터져요?
이게 무슨 소리죠?
What is that in the background?
지금 '스타트랙' 봐요?
Are you watching Star Trek?
So did you break Julie's heart?
어떻게 됐어?
줄리하고는 결별했어?
그래
It was horrible. She cried, I cried.
She threw things, they hit me.
끔찍했어, 줄리도 울고,
나도 울고, 물건 던지길래 맞았어
I did the right thing.
난 옳은 일을 한 거야
So Spock actually hugs his father?
'스팍'이 아버지를 안았어요?
Hey, do you guys have
너희들 혹시...
- 안녕
Where you going?
어디 가?
방금 들어왔어
줄리에게 갔다 왔거든
I just got back...
...from Julie's.
No, no.
아냐, 그렇게 생각하지 마
그 반대라고
It's not what you think.
It's the other thing.
Well, what's the other thing?
What do I think?
반대라니?
내가 뭘 생각하는데?
Well....
그게...
줄리랑 헤어졌대!
He broke up with Julie!
Well, go hug her, for God's sakes!
뭐 해, 어서 가서 안아 줘!
Really?
- 정말이야?
- 그래
Really.
It's always been you, Rach.
항상 널 사랑했어, 레이첼
세상에...
Oh, God.
Oh, this is good.
너무 좋아
-This is really good.
-I know. I know.
알아, 뭐랄까...
It's almost....
What do you say we take a walk?
Just us. Not them.
우리 산책이나 갈까?
재들 없는 곳으로
-Let me get my coat.
-Okay. No, hey!
- 코트 가져올게
- 그래, 잠깐만!
I'll get your coat.
내가 갖다 줄게
알았어
내 코트를 갖다 준대
He's going to get my coat.
He's going to get my coat, Joey!
로스가 말야, 조이!
Joey, I can't believe this!
This is unbelievable!
믿어지지가 않아!
-What's that?
-What? Nothing!
- 저게 뭐야?
- 뭐가? 아냐!
- 내 이름이 있던데?
- 아냐, 없어
-I saw my name. What is it?
-No, no, see? See?
It's printing!
프린터가 작동된다!
프린터가 켜졌어!
Let me see!
뭔데? 어서 보여 줘
Hey, someone order a coat?
코트 시키셨나요?
챈들러가 내 얘길 쓰고
보여 주지를 않아
Chandler wrote something about me
and won't let me see.
He won't? He won't!
챈들러가 그런단 말야?
네가 요즘 쓰는
그 단편소설 말이야?
Because isn't that...
...the short story you were writing?
맞아, 내 단편소설이야
Yes, it is a short story...
...that I was writing.
And I'm in it?
Let me read it.
내가 주인공이야?
그럼 읽어 봐야지
안 돼!
No!
- 어서!
- 챈들러, 네가 읽어 줘
-Come on!
-Hey, why don't you read it to her?
All right.
좋아!
"It was summer.
여름이었다
And it was hot.
아주 더웠다
Rachel was there.
거기 레이철이 있었다
외로운 회색 소파
A lonely gray couch.
'Oh, look!' cried Ned.
'저걸 봐요! '
네드가 울부짖었다
And the kingdom was his forever.
The end!"
그의 영원한 왕국이었다
끝!
겨우 그걸 썼어?
That's all you wrote?
You're the worst writer in the world!
넌 엉터리 작가야, 짜샤!
다들 그만둬
This isn't funny anymore.
There's something about me
on that paper, and I want to see it.
나에 대해 적혀 있으니
난 읽어 봐야겠어!
아냐!
No, you don't.
All right, fine. If you guys want
to be children, that's fine.
얘들처럼 놀아 보자고?
그럼 좋다고
안 보면 그만이니까!
I do not need to see it!
What is this?
이게 뭐야?
That is....
그건...
What is this?
로스, 이게 뭐야?
- 갈게
- 행운을 빈다
-Thank you.
-Good luck.
Okay. Just remember how crazy
I am about you, okay?
내가 널 사랑하는 것만
생각하라고
"Kind of ditzy"?
생각이 없다고?
외모에만 신경 쓰고
"Too into her looks"?
철이 없다고?
"Spoiled"?
'약간'이라고 했는데
멍청한 놈이 빼먹었나 봐
A little spoiled. He was supposed
to type "little," the idiot!
"Just a waitress"?
일개 웨이트리스?
Now that was....
그건 어디까지나
돌려서 표현한 건데...
I mean, as opposed to....
Okay, is this over yet? Rach?
아직도 남았어?
I do not have chubby ankles!
내 발목 안 두꺼워!
그게 아냐!
No! I
Okay, look at the other side.
Look at Julie's column.
줄리의 것도 읽어 봐!
"She's not Rachem"?
'레이쳄'이 아냐?
'레이쳄'이 대체 뭐야?
What the hell's a Rachem?
웨이트리스는 모르는
고생물학 용어인가?
Is that a stupid paleontology word...
... I wouldn't know,
because I'm just a waitress?
Rach, come on!
그게 아냐, 레이첼!
'레이첼'이 아니라고
오타가...
It's "She's not Rachel"!
She's not....
레이첼?
일기! 바로 그거였어!
My diary! Brilliant!
If I'd said it was my diary,
she wouldn't have made me read it.
내 일기라고 했으면
읽겠다고 안 했을 텐데
That's true. You'd be a great person
to have around after an emergency.
맞아
넌 정말 뒷북치는 데
천재적인 소질이 있어
그런 목록을 만들다니
로스가 심했어
I cannot believe Ross
even made this list.
-I know.
-What a dinkus!
- 맞아
- 왕 싸가지!
로스만 나무라지 마
Hey, cut him some slack.
It was Chandler's idea.
챈들러의 생각이었다고
What?
- 뭐?
- 그 말이 왜 안 나오나 했어
Oh, good. I was hoping
that would come up.
This was your idea?
네 생각이었다고?
생각해 봐, 이런 일에는
다 그만한 이유가 있어
Let's get some perspective here.
These things happen for a reason.
Yeah. You!
바로 너!
Pheebs, back me up. You believe
in that karma crap, don't you?
피비, 네가 말해 봐
너도 '카르마'를 믿지?
By the way, good luck
in your next life as a dung beetle.
사후에 행운을 빌어
풍뎅이로 태어날 테니
Rach!
레이첼!
Hey! Open up! Please?
제발 문 열어!
When somebody does not buzz you in,
Ross, that means, "Go away."
누가 문을 안 열어 주면
가라는 소리야
비상계단으로
올라오란 소리가 아니고!
It doesn't mean,
"Climb up the fire escape."
네 장점에 대해서
읽어 주고 싶어!
I just want to read you
your "Pro List."
관심 없어!
Not interested.
첫째, 네가 우는 모습!
"Number one:
the way you cry at game shows.
Number two:
how much you love your friends.
둘째, 넌 친구들을
진정으로 사랑하고!
Number three: the way you play
with your hair when you're nervous.
셋째, 긴장했을 때
머리 만지는 모습!
Number four: how brave you are
for starting your life over.
넷째, 인생을 재설계하는
네 배짱!
다섯째, 벤과 잘 놀아주고!
Number five:
how great you are with Ben.
Number six: the way you smell."
여섯째, 네 체취는
정말 끝내줘!
로스, 거기서 뭐 해?
What are you doing?
You want to open the window?
- 창문 좀 열어 줄래?
- 참!
Oh, yeah.
-What are you doing out there?
-I'm....
- 거기서 뭐 하고 있었어?
- 그냥...
얼마나 추웠을까!
이럴 때 좋은 게 있어
You must be freezing.
You know what you need?
김이 모락모락 나는
핫 마콜릿 한잔!
How about a nice, steaming
cup of hot Macholate?
Come on, open up.
레이첼, 문 열어!
Rach, come on.
You gotta give me another chance.
레이첼, 부탁이야
다시 기회를 줘
No.
싫어!
-No?
-That's what I said.
- 싫어?
- 그래, 그렇게 말했어
Maybe we should go.
우린 갈게
아냐, 갈 필요 없어
우린 할 얘기 끝났어
You don't have to go.
We're done.
네 기분은 알지만...
I know how you must
넌 몰라, 로스!
No! You don't, Ross.
Imagine the worst things
you think about yourself.
생각해 봐
너의 가장 안 좋은 점을
네가 가장 좋아하는
사람이 들먹이면서
How would you feel if the person
you trusted most in the world...
... not only thinks them too...
멀리할 구실로 이용하면
그 기분이 어떻겠어?
... but actually uses them
as reasons not to be with you.
No, but see, I want to be with you
in spite of all those things.
난 그런 것에 상관없어
너와 있고 싶어
Well, that's mighty big of you.
아량도 넓으셔라
가지 말라니까!
I said, don't go!
You know what?
이거 알아?
If it were the other way around, there
is nothing you could put on a list...
반대로 네가 그랬더라면
난 웃고 넘겼을 거야
...that would make me
not want to be with you.
그게 우리 차이점이야
Well, then I guess that's
the difference between us.
See, I'd never make a list.
난 목록을 안 만들거든
I never know how long to wait
in this situation before you can talk.
얼마나 더 기다려야
말해도 괜찮은 거야?
Maybe a little longer.
좀더 기다리자
요리법의 재료 양이
맞지가 않아요
In these recipes,
the quantities may seem unusual.
Like these coconut Macholate
holiday nut bars?
코코넛 마콜릿 땅콩 바의
경우에는
I've indicated four cups of coconut
and four cups of nuts...
코코넛 4컵, 땅콩가루 4컵
마콜릿 한 스푼이에요
...and only one tablespoon
of Macholate.
Doesn't matter.
- 상관없어
- 네?
Our FDA approval didn't come through.
식약청 승인이 안 났어
Something about laboratory rats.
실험실에 쥐가 어쩌니
하면서 말야
- 정말 큰일이네요
- 그래
Gosh, I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Anyhow, here's your check.
어쨌거나 여기 급여야
Thank you for all the trouble
you went through.
그간 수고했어
Listen, you didn't eat a lot of it
while you were cooking, did you?
설마 요리하면서
먹지는 않았겠지?
Well, I ate some.
조금 먹었는데요
조금은 괜찮아
많이는 아니니까 말야
Oh, some is fine.
Some is not a lot.
알았어요
So it doesn't burn
when you pee, does it?
소변볼 때 가렵지 않던가?
여보세요?
나야
Is that him again?
또 로스야?
Tell him I'd come to the phone,
but my ankles are weighing me down.
발목이 너무 무거워서
전화 못 받는다고 해
I don't think this is the best time.
지금은 때가 안 좋아
Look, can you do something for me?
부탁하나 들어줄래?
그럼, 뭔데?
Sure. What?
알았어
All right.
음악 들을까?
Music?
Sure.
다음은 로스가 레이첼에게
보내는 곡입니다
The next one's dedicated
to Rachel from Ross.
Rachel, he wants you to know
he's sorry for what he did...
레이첼, 로스는 자기의
잘못을 뉘우치면서
...and he hopes you can forgive him.
당신의 용서를 바랍니다
See the stones set in your eyes
당신의 눈에 박힌 돌
당신의 몸에 박힌 가시
See the thorn twist in your side
I'll wait for you
당신을 기다리겠어요
책략과 운명의 장난
Sleight of hand and twist of fate
On a bed of nails she makes me wait
못으로 만들어진 침대에서
당신을 기다리겠어요
And I'll wait without you
레이첼이 전화로 로스가
한 짓을 알려 왔네요
We've just gotten a call from Rachel
and she told us what Ross did.
It's pretty appalling.
And, Ross, if you're listening...
너무 심했군요
로스, 듣고 계시겠죠?
...I don't want to play
your song anymore.
신청곡을 끊겠어요
Why don't we devote our time
to a couple that stands a chance?
기회가 있는 커플들을
소개합니다
Avery, Michelle's sorry
she hit you with her car...
에이버리, 미셸이 차로
치어서 미안하다면서
...and she hopes you two
will work it out.
화해를 바라고 있어요
나만의 비밀을 털어놓을
나만의 공간
There's a room where
I can go
And tell my secrets to
바로 내 방이라네
In my room
어서 와요
다시 와 줘서 고마워요
Thanks for coming in again.
도덕심이고 뭐고
당장 돈이 필요해서요
Not at all. I have no morals,
and I need the cash.
거울을 보는 기분이네요
It's like I'm looking in a mirror.
'피쉬타치오'예요
Anyway, they're called Fish-tachios.
피스타치오와 맛은
똑같지만
They taste exactly
like pistachios...
생선쓰레기로 만들었죠
... but they're made
of reconstituted fish bits.
한번 먹어 봐요
Here, try one.
- 그러죠
- 알레르기는 없겠죠?
-All right.
-You're not allergic to anything?
Cat hair.
고양이털이요
이런, 미안해요
Oh, sorry.